Hey, and welcome back to living [music]
in Central Texas. If you watched my dash
cam tour of Temple, [music] Texas, we're
picking up right where we left off on
West Adams. Today, we're doing a dash
cam tour of Belton, Texas, one of the
[music] most sought-after communities in
all of Central Texas. We'll be touring
downtown Belton, the historic district,
University of Mary Hardin-Baylor,
[music]
some local Belton favorites. We'll be
going over Lake Belton, which is my
personal favorite,
>> [music]
>> and even touring some communities so you
can get a feel of what it's really like
living here.
>> [music]
>> So, buckle up. Let's go for a ride.
>> Okay, [music] everyone. Welcome back.
I'm really excited to be doing this tour
today. The weather is [music] absolutely
a phenomenal, and I think it's going to
give you a great idea of the difference
between Temple and Belton. So, during
our last tour, we came up the other
direction. We came up from Temple, down
West Adams. [music]
And now, we're actually going the
opposite direction, headed into true
Belton proper. [music]
So, West Adams is basically that main
corridor through Temple into Belton.
It's got all of your major shopping on
[music] West Adams. Um where we just
were that I showed you, we have some
boutiques. You have a bunch of different
types of restaurants, Indian, Thai,
pizza. You have some more popular chains
here, [music]
like Chick-fil-A. You have about a dozen
car washes. And uh
a lot of you have some medical
facilities
>> [music]
>> on West Adams. And of course, from this
location, 10 minutes from the children's
hospital, 10 minutes from [music]
Baylor Scott & White, the main facility,
as well as 10 to 12 [music] minutes from
the VA hospital. So, really great
location. I'd say a lot of people, when
they move here, are [music] interested
in West Adams because a, it might be
it's kind of weird how Temple works
[music] or how this area works. You can
be in
city of Temple but be part of Belton
ISD, so the Belton school district. And
even if you don't have kids [music] and
that's not a priority to you, the
desirability
and the cost per square foot on homes
goes up in Belton ISD.
So where we are right now as we're
headed down West Adams, you can see it's
super green. There's a bunch of parks,
still a lot of infrastructure [music]
and building happening here. But in
either direction, you're going to have a
lot of newer communities.
Now up this way we're going to head into
Belton. We are still technically in
Temple, but we are in Belton ISD [music]
at this point. Now if we were to
continue going straight up West Adams,
we would be going into Morgan's Point
area, which is still Belton, again kind
of confusing, but right by the lake. And
I will be taking you over Lake Belton.
If we were to go up West Adams, we could
go left on Morgan's Point Road and go
over Lake Belton, but we're going to do
a different route because I want to show
you true Belton, downtown Belton, and
then at the very [music] end we'll swing
back and loop back over the lake so you
can get the true
view of that. I will say that is
probably my biggest love for this area
is Lake Belton. I think it's a hidden
gem.
Um I I love Dead [music] Fish Grill on
Lake Belton. Their food is
okay.
>> [music]
>> They're going to hate me for saying
that. Their food is okay, but
their
uh
>> [music]
>> cocktails, I really love their
margaritas. So if you're in the area, um
I highly recommend their DFG Dead
[music] Fish Grill and Margarita.
But returning here onto 317, so 3
going in the opposite direction if we
were to [music] turn right. What is
that, Raquel, north?
>> East.
>> Heading north, that would have take us
[music] up to
like Waco. We would go through back
roads. You'd get in go past Troy, Moody,
which are some awesome [music]
smaller communities that
if you're looking for maybe some bigger
land
sorry, some more land, then that might
be the direction that you'd be
interested in going.
More rural.
You take this all the way up, you'll
also catch 14 if you need [music] easy
access to Fort Hood.
That's probably 20 minutes from 14.
>> [music]
>> And then also I-35. This will take you
to I-35 if you're looking [music]
to get to Austin, which is probably a
good hour away.
And Waco, which is [music] probably 40
to 45 minutes north.
14 will also take you to Nolanville.
35 [music] is going to take you to
Salado, Georgetown, Round Rock, some of
those other areas close to here [music]
as well. So, off of 317, we're going to
have some more established [music]
communities, but also a bunch of newer
communities.
On the right here, they're building a
bunch of chains. [music] They just put
in a Panda Express. Of course, this is
another Starbucks. This is the Starbucks
off of in [music] Belton. McDonald's.
There's a big Walmart Supercenter right
here off of
sorry, 317. [music]
And then on the left, we're going to
have HEB.
>> Store brand [music] is, in my opinion,
just as good if not better than the name
brand product.
>> Lake Road, if we were to go right here,
is going to take us to Lake Belton. On
the right, [music]
you you can see Walmart. On the left,
this is where HEB is.
So, in terms of medical, Baylor Scott &
White is our main medical facility here.
Everything's integrated. So, if you go
to one of their small [music] clinics,
the hospital, any of the other small
clinics, the providers, the specialties,
they can all access
>> [music]
>> your MyChart and your app. So, I really
love that feature, honestly, [music]
um because you're not having to fax
records. It's all in one system.
And so, they have a bunch of clinics.
There's a clinic [music]
right here. So, for example, like when I
was pregnant, I went here to have my
blood work done, or I could go off of
the one off of West Adams. My general
practitioner's off of West Adams. You
know, you don't have to
to go to the main hospital for
everything, which I think is really
great.
We are truly in Belton now. We are not
in Temple anymore. One of the big
drawing factors to this area is the
University of Mary Hardin-Baylor.
[music] It was founded in 1845, and it's
one of the oldest universities in all
[music] of Texas. I honestly think this
is a major economic driver to this area.
In downtown Belton, you'll see
>> [music]
>> um a lot of people purchasing, for
example, investment properties to rent
out to um the students, faculty, plus a
lot of people that just want to buy in
downtown because they love living in the
historic district. There's some really
neat homes down here.
See the purple and gold? We're coming up
to UMHB.
I'm going to do a little loop-de-loo
down here so you can take a look.
Beautiful campus.
Just truly in the heart of downtown
Belton, or
truly in the heart [music] of Belton.
My husband was born and raised in this
area, and he actually went to University
of Mary Hardin-Baylor. So funny cuz
[music] he did all of his undergrad
there and then ended up getting up
What is that called? Like a trade
two-year
trade degree.
Okay, so we're going to come back here
on Main Street. It's 12:57 [music]
right now.
Middle of the afternoon on a Wednesday.
So Wednesday and see around lunchtime.
So this road is a little bit busier.
This is kind of like a busier
view of the road since it is lunchtime.
All right, so we're going to be headed
into downtown Belton. We're about to hit
Central.
On the right here is my go-to hair
stylist, Ali at Beautiful Salon. [music]
Been seeing her for probably 10 years
and absolutely love her. There's [music]
also Woodhouse Day Spa, which is a
fantastic
spa for, you know,
massages and waxing and all of the
things. And then
>> [music]
>> right here, how beautiful is this? This
is the Bell County Courthouse.
Even since the time that I've lived
here, I've been here about 11 years now,
they have This place is just really
[music] established. They're really
doing a lot with downtown Belton and I
have a whole video on downtown Belton
and
>> [music]
>> of course I missed some of it. I
couldn't get it all, but you have
Italian restaurant. They have a new
restaurant right here called Hella.
There's pizza.
Beautiful courthouse.
On the right, on the opposite side of
the courthouse is Water Street Waffle
Company, which is my favorite breakfast
spots.
And then right up here is a little
pocket. It's the Gin. [music]
This was also in my video of downtown
Belton.
But you have Scores, [music] which is a
sports bar, Wings, Pizza, Corona's, De
Oro, which is a Mexican [music]
restaurant. The Gin is really cool. It
overlooks Nolan Creek, which is
absolutely beautiful.
Actually, let's go take a peek at Nolan
Creek.
They also host little events here at the
Gin. You [music] can rent out their
venue to do, you know, bridal showers,
baby showers.
I think Nolan Creek is just [music] so
cool, super beautiful. As you can see
behind me, there's the creek. You can go
to the Gin, look over the water,
>> [music]
>> really awesome. And then there's
actually the trail all the way to kind
it. You could go on walks, you could go
down uh a lot further and there's
um a splash pad, playground, tons of
walking trails with covered trees,
really pretty. It's awesome.
Another awesome part of downtown Belton
is they do a lot of events. So, there's
the big 4th of July parade, they do a
Christmas stroll, uh just a lot of
[music] events.
You have Cochran Blair and Potts, which
is, I think, one of the oldest
department stores in this area, really
awesome boutique style. You want to
check out inside.
We have Miller's Smokehouse, which is
super popular for their barbecue.
>> Naru Nias Thai, which is my favorite
Thai food. They also deliver.
Where else should we go down here?
Go left. There's some boutiques and
stuff down here.
>> Mhm. Pink Bulldog.
>> Mhm.
>> What's that off of?
>> Mhm. Belton Christian Youth Center.
That is really popular. I think they
have a bunch of summer camps and
whatnot.
Where's that new Railroad restaurant?
>> Is it on second?
>> Level.
Let's go down here.
Go. Okay. So, you have Pink Bulldog
Boutique. That's a cute little boutique
here. Nolan Creek Brewery.
Bunch of little hidden gems tucked away
back here.
Crooked Cactus Co.
Muscoby Coffee. I didn't even know that
was open down here.
The Beltonian Theater. I think it's
under new ownership, so they're working
on that cool little
uh
movie theater.
You can just see all of the charm down
here. Everyone loves it.
I'm really proud of what they're
creating.
Here we go.
Oak fire pizza.
Arisha's and then on the right Pinky's
cocktail lounge that's new is there a
stop sign on that side? [music]
And then Railway Express Diner really
great food.
And there's [music] actually a speak
easy down here.
What's that called?
Drawing a blank. It's in the pizza
restaurant.
Blackbird yes a blackbird [music] is a
speak easy.
And it's a bookstore so you can have
cocktails
get a book.
Okay now I'm going to take you to
[music] a super super popular community
for this area.
Did they close down Fry's?
>> Yeah.
>> I didn't know that.
It was I loved it.
>> It was really good. The bad Ernie's is
right across the street.
>> I've been there.
>> [laughter]
>> What's that bad Ernie's?
>> The best [music] breakfast burrito ever.
Yes see okay look at the exterior of the
building.
>> Okay Raquel says don't look at the
exterior of the building but go to bad
Ernie's for the best breakfast burrito.
Just don't look.
>> [laughter]
>> Okay now we're heading on to 14.
We're actually on the front edge road to
14.
Excuse me.
But out this way you have Nolanville so
again you take 14
west
to Nolanville
big community and there is Bella Charca.
You keep going, you're going to get
Harker Heights and Killeen.
So, we're coming [music] up to the loop.
This is Loop 121.
There are some newer communities right
off of the loop, Sky Crest, [music]
View at Bell Meadows.
Contracted quite a few in there. They're
all doing some really great deals. If
you're interested, let me know. You got
to be careful with those builders,
y'all, though. They'll tell you a price,
but generally, we can really tell you
what builders we've worked with
recently, what deals we can get you,
what they're willing to put in in terms
of concessions, fixed interest rates,
little add additives like
lines, fridges. We're just going to take
the frontage road, y'all, cuz it's a lot
easier than hopping [music] on the 14
right now.
Something that I adjusted to when I
moved here was all these frontage roads,
and
now I kind of love them cuz you can skip
the freeway if you need to.
But, you can even see middle of the
afternoon, and you can glimpse over to
14 right now, and it's not busy.
On the right here, you have Sendera,
indoor shooting range.
There's another range. What's that
[music] one called? Flippers? The
Webbers. Yes, and that's off of 35
headed towards Waco.
That one's an outdoor range.
Now, this community is super, super
popular for that I'm going to be taking
you to is very popular for a variety of
reasons.
One is going to be the community itself
and the amenities that it offers.
[music]
This community has a walking trail. It's
one of only two communities in this area
that I know of that has genuine walking
trails.
There's a creek [music] that runs
through. It's called Three Creeks.
There's a creek that runs through that
you can walk and they replaced the
volleyball course with a park
playground.
There's a pavilion.
But I think one of the biggest reasons
is its proximity and location being
right off of I-14. It's
20 minutes 15-20 minutes into downtown
Belton, 15-20 minutes to Temple,
20 minutes to Fort Hood. So, you get a
variety of people and professions in in
this area and they're right next to
Stillhouse Hollow Lake. So, our area has
Belton Lake
and then it has Stillhouse Hollow Lake.
You actually come out of Three Creeks,
go left and you're right in front of
Stillhouse.
But there are also a variety of
builders. So, you have
all of these are pretty much production
builders. Some smaller production
builders being, I don't know, Tippit
Homes. Um
really beautiful builder, but then you
have your production builders DR Horton,
Omega,
Stylecraft.
Carothers is our luxury builder here.
But because of that, you get a community
with all of those amenities, the
location, [music]
and a variety of price points. So, it's
very affordable for entry-level homes,
but then also more high-end luxury
[music] options as well.
So, you can see right up there is still
Health Lake and then we get to choose
the view. This is Three Creeks.
Really pretty entrance.
Still a ton of development. So,
interesting thing is
a lot of the resale homes are competing
with the builders because the builders
are still offering a lot of incentives
to get their inventory moved.
So, you can get a really great deal on
resale
and new construction, just depending on
which route you want to go. You can see
along the side full length sidewalks.
And I'll show you just the exterior view
of the a few of the different builders.
So, you can maybe even see from the
outside what some of that looks like.
There's a lot of roundabouts in here,
which that is not something I feel is
very popular to
Texas are roundabouts.
But, they label each of these sections.
So, there's Cold Creek, Northridge and
Emerald Pointe, Chalk Ridge.
But, this first one Had Waters right
here. You can see they're still building
a ton.
So, D.R. Horton builds a lot in here.
Gotten so and N Style Craft. Tippit is
[music] in the back, but I've gotten
some really smoking deals for my clients
in this area in particular. So,
definitely reach out. Make sure you're
represented. Their sales reps aren't
They're very kind, but they represent
the builder and they are not going to
get you the best deal.
And of course, all these builders still
pay for our commission, so it doesn't
really hurt you at all to make sure that
you're well represented.
Bunch of these are going to be D.R.
Horton
and Stylecraft.
Now on the right here
we have Carothers, which is that luxury
builder. Oops, sorry. Quick turn.
But you can still get the three-car
garages. You can see their full stone
exterior, stone and brick exterior.
Variety of
elevations, which is that look on the
front. [music]
Different colors in stonework.
But
they they're still selling in here and
I'm even seeing some resales as we're
driving.
Some of these have some really beautiful
backyards with no rear neighbors.
And [music] Carothers, they build a lot
of the things that they put into their
homes standard are an upgrade for other
builders. So just really, really
beautiful.
But a little bit more price per square
foot. You know, you get what you pay
for.
On the other side we have Stylecraft and
Omega.
And again, all of these
walking trails and sidewalks with little
doggie
trash bags, poop stations along the way.
Again, you're in Salado ISD. You're
still in that Belton school district,
even though you're getting really close
to the Harker Heights area.
So Northridge Emerald Pointe, I'm going
to take you guys by that first pavilion
and walking trail playground [music]
area that really sets this community
apart.
So tucked away in this community, oh,
you might not be able to get it from
this side. We'll have to do it on the
way out, maybe.
Cuz I want to show these ones.
But this area tucked away back here,
these are some more
established homes on larger lots
that have been here for a minute. You
can see these little paths down
and
true little hiking trails tucked down
here.
Wow, what a great view. They have a
whole canyon view.
Beautiful.
Can you pull up right here?
Okay. And take your vehicle. Yeah.
Okay.
All right. So we are going down to
How cool is this? So if you live in this
community, you can take your car, you
can walk down here. It says, "No
trespassing. Three [music] Creeks
residents only and realtors." I saw that
super fine print.
Feel like you're going on an adventure.
But there's walking trails that segway
off.
This is your pavilion. So if you want to
do birthday parties, have a little
get-together here. Park and walk.
Okay, I wanted to hop out and show this
to you cuz I think it's such a selling
point to the community. [music] This
used to be a volleyball court and I
don't think anyone really used it. This
is far more practical in my opinion. It
has this workout section, a [music] true
playground, and then there's the creek
down below. You can smell the creek as
you're standing here. And then up on the
hill you have the pavilion, but looks
really great, really functional.
All right. Now, we [music] just turned
on to 121, Loop 121 off
I-14, [music]
and you can see on the right the Belton
sign says welcome to Belton.
So, this is just [music] a tiny bit
west, like couple streets over from Main
Street that we were [music] just at.
They run parallel to one another. But,
I'm going to head over and go ahead and
show you Lake [music] Belton. So, one of
the biggest reasons people move to this
area is the lifestyle. [music]
Now, of course, we are the largest
medical hub between Austin and Dallas,
uh close [music] to Fort Hood, in
between Waco and Austin. That proximity
is all really big selling points to this
area.
But,
>> [music]
>> the lifestyle of Lake Belton, sorry, the
lifestyle of Belton is just huge.
There's just so many recreational
opportunities,
boating, fishing, hiking. FM 93 right
here also runs [music] straight through
Belton and loops you over into Temple.
So, just a ton of overlap. If [music]
you're considering Temple, definitely
consider Belton and vice versa because
there's there's just overlap. I was
really glad that I was able to get some
video today because the weather was just
Well, it's hot.
>> [music]
>> It is hot. It is hot and humid. Let's
Let's say it.
90° outside, but
it feels a little [music] bit toastier
with the humidity.
I personally do not like cold bones, so
[music] Texas is really perfect.
Definitely don't get a lot of cold bones
here.
Does it [music] ever snow here? Um no,
not really. There's
maybe during winter we might get a
couple days of
slaking, snow flaking, but just doesn't
stick.
But it doesn't stay cold here. [music]
Not a lot of snow. We have We did have a
couple like two ice storms [music] in
the 10 years that I've been here, 11
years that I've been here.
So there are two high schools [music] in
the area. There is Belton High School
and Lake Belton High School. Belton High
School's the one that was here first.
And then Lake Belton is going to be more
out towards Morgan's Point Resort.
On the left [music] you have Belton High
School. So we're going left, but what if
we were to have gone right
you can see right, I can actually see
it, it's Main Street. So where [music] I
showed you
Walmart,
HEB,
Main Street [music] being that main Main
Street turns to 317,
which runs
north [music] and south
through Belton. I've had my baby in the
car with us this entire recording, and
she hasn't
I actually had to peek back there and
make sure she was still breathing, and
she is, so
real thrilled
about that. [music] So in front is River
Place. That's an established community,
super super cute.
But how pretty is this? All the trees.
It's nice and green outside this time of
year. I think this should give you a
really great idea of Belton at its
finest. Now in my I did a video not too
long ago on best communities [music]
near Lake Belton, and I focused a lot on
the Morgan's Point side, on the north
side of Lake Belton. This is the south
side of Lake Belton, which they're
minutes from each other, but you've got
[music]
Goasan's Ranch, Red Rocky Hill, Ralph E
Fair Canyon right here, [music] Chisholm
Trail Park, River Place was the one I
just told you about, but those are all
kind of right here in this little
triangle.
If you're still looking [music] to be
close to the lake and in Belton. Oh
yeah, Miller Springs. So Miller Springs
is a really big park right here, walking
trails. We have a ton of parks.
And then in front of me is a Dead Fish
Grill where I was telling you they have
the best
>> [music]
>> best margaritas.
But
I love going out there when it's
>> [music]
>> cooler cuz inside they have a full
window that you can overlook the lake
and when the weather's nice you can
[music] sit outside on the patio and
overlook the lake and it's the best view
in this area.
Okay, and then
this is a Belton Lake.
So headed over Belton Lake right here on
the right, we have Miller Springs.
Just the other side of it. So there are
a couple different access points [music]
to Miller Springs.
You can see people walking along there,
just miles of trails.
Live Oakridge Park on the [music] left,
you've got RV parks out there.
Miller Springs, we'll turn back around
and I'll I'll show you Miller Springs,
but if [music] you take this road down
you take this this is Morgan's Point
Road and you take it down and you and
you head into Morgan's Point Resort that
and again I have some videos of that up
on my page if you would like more of it,
a deep dive. [music]
And then right before we get to West
Adams, so you get to West Adams, which
is the one that runs
through Temple and Belton. [music]
We'll hit Adams first, and then just
after that is when you head into
Morgan's Point. So, [music] you can
maybe see how it's all looped and
connected. And don't forget, on my
website, I have a really awesome map
of this area. If you [music]
are a little confused on where we are
and
what's around us, [music] that's a very
helpful map.
Belton, Texas has really managed to
maintain its small-town [music] feel
while benefiting from the major growth
happening here in Central Texas. Between
its historic district, Lake [music]
Belton, UMHB, Fort Hood, and its easy
access for major employers and
healthcare, it's really easy to see why
so many people are calling Belton, Texas
home.
Thank you so much for joining me [music]
on this dashcam tour today. I hope you
found it helpful. If you would like more
information on relocating to the Central
[music] Texas area, you can find all my
contact information below. I'd love to
be your guide. Till next time.